<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://tonyz97.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://tonyz97.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-06-28T11:12:20-04:00</updated><id>https://tonyz97.github.io/</id><title type="html">Tony Zhang</title><subtitle>Personal website of Tony Zhang. Computer Science (CS) major at Cornell University</subtitle><author><name>Tony Zhang</name><email>nz97@cornell.edu</email></author><entry><title type="html">My summer internship and writing my first django app</title><link href="https://tonyz97.github.io/2017/06/My-Summer-Internship-and-Writing-My-First-Django-App.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My summer internship and writing my first django app" /><published>2017-06-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-06-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://tonyz97.github.io/2017/06/My%20Summer%20Internship%20and%20Writing%20My%20First%20Django%20App</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://tonyz97.github.io/2017/06/My-Summer-Internship-and-Writing-My-First-Django-App.html">&lt;p&gt;####My Summer Position
This summer, I’m doing a research internship in sunny Singapore.  In particular, I’m working at the &lt;a href=&quot;%22https://www.a-star.edu.sg/ihpc%22/IHPC%20home%20page&quot;&gt;Institute of High Performance Computing (IHPC),&lt;/a&gt;  a research institute under the parent company that is the Agency for Science, Technology and Research, known as A*STAR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To many who are probably unfamiliar, &lt;a href=&quot;%22https://www.a-star.edu.sg%22/%20A*STAR%20home%20page&quot;&gt;A*STAR&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;“is Singapore’s lead public sector agency that spearheads economic-oriented research to advance scientific discovery and develop innovative technology”&lt;/em&gt;. It’s a pretty cool environment, and I am working on some machine learning projects with my supervisor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;####My First Django Web App
The projects in which I’m involved are all about automating patient diagnosis through Machine Learning and Computer Vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first task this summer was to create a ‘proof-of-concept’ web application that would demonstrate to hospitals the use of a lung cancer identification algorithm our team developed.  This algorithm is a neural net that takes in a set of DICOM images. A dicom image (Digital Imaging and Communications in Medicine) is the standard output format for X-Ray and CAT scans. An image is 2-D slice, and a set of images from a CAT scan gives a 3-D rendering of,  say,  a lung. Our algorithm then spits out the xyz-coordinates of where the cancerous tumors might be located in said lung.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tumor identification is traditionally done by the human eye, so it is hoped that our program can automate the process. What’s needed now is a web-based platform to serve our program to the customers. That is my job to build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my delight, there already exists an open-source medical image viewer in JavaScript lying around on GitHub. We fondly call it the &lt;a href=&quot;%22https://github.com/rii-mango/Papaya%22/Papaya%20DICOM%20Viewer&quot;&gt;Papaya Viewer&lt;/a&gt;. No need to reinvent the wheel then!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a good overview of the problem, I could zoom in on the specifications. I need to develop a web-application that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lets the user upload a set of dicom files&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run our cancer-identification program server-side&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Display the dicom images with Papaya, with additional buttons that let the user  zoom in onto regions identified by our detection algorithm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My web development being experience close to naught (this was before I built this website), I got to work looking up possible tools I could use. I knew it had to be dynamic application, so my choices included Ruby on Rails and Django. Since I fell in love with the &lt;em&gt;sheer awesomeness of Python&lt;/em&gt; last semester writing OS projects (synchronization &amp;amp; network programming), I went with Django. 
(I might do a future post about why I think Python is great, and why it replaced Java as my language of choice)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amazing quality of Django’s documentation got me up to speed quickly, and a day of tutorials and fiddling later, I was quickly building my first web application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d show you how beautiful it looks, but in reality though, it’s a proof-of-concept, and minimally viable demo, so we’re wasting no time dressing it up. It’s only crucial that it works. Which it wonderfully does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But most important to me personally, is that I learned the process of creating and deploying a web application, such as url management, utilizing modularity in HTML templates, and how MVC is applied in web development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also learned what a framework like Django was about. It’s like the inverse of an API, where instead of you calling the the API, the framework calls your code (see &lt;a href=&quot;%22https://martinfowler.com/articles/injection.html%22/Inversion%20of%20Control&quot;&gt;Inversion of Control&lt;/a&gt;). It’s an MVC pattern with the C already in place, and you provide the M and the V. A chef-for-hire where where you just provide the ingredients. It is awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I get to come back to this project, I want to add features such as a database to store patient data. And for that, Django is perfect.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tony Zhang</name><email>nz97@cornell.edu</email></author><summary type="html">####My Summer Position This summer, I’m doing a research internship in sunny Singapore. In particular, I’m working at the Institute of High Performance Computing (IHPC), a research institute under the parent company that is the Agency for Science, Technology and Research, known as A*STAR.</summary></entry></feed>